A Guide to the Hao Wang papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA274
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts, Notes, and Notebooks, 3
  - Selection and Instruction, Includes: "Perceptrons: An Introduction to Computational Geometry" by Marvin Minsky and Seymour Papert “Mathematics and Deconstruction” “Selective Networks Capable of Representative Transformations, Limited Generalizations, and Associative Memory” by Gerald M. Edelman and George N. Reeke, Jr. “Selective Networks and Recognition Automata” by George N. Reeke, Jr., and Gerald M. Edelman “Recursive Evolution” by O.E. Rössler “Through a Computer Darkly: Group Selection and Higher Brain Function” by Gerald M. Edelman (Box 124, Folder 1581)
  - "The Separation of Wish and Fact" (Box 124, Folder 1582)
  - Set Theoretical Exercises, 1963-1964 (Box 124, Folder 1583)
  - Set Theory, Revision Copy (Box 124, Folder 1584)
  - Set (Useless) (Box 124, Folder 1585)
  - S.G. Shanker (Box 125, Folder 1586)
  - Henry M. Sheffer (Box 125, Folder 1587)
  - J.C. Shepherdson (Box 125, Folder 1588)
  - "Short Definitions of the Ordinals" by Kenneth R. Brown and Hao Wang (Box 125, Folder 1589)
  - Shaligram Singh (Box 125, Folder 1590)
  - Skolem (1 of 2) (Box 125, Folder 1591)
  - Skolem (2 of 2) (Box 125, Folder 1592)
  - Skolem (Box 125, Folder 1593)
  - "Skolem and Gödel" (Box 125, Folder 1594)
  - The Skolem Lecture, Oslo, February 19, 1993 (Box 126, Folder 1595)
  - Thoralf Skolem (1 of 2) (Box 126, Folder 1596)
  - Thoralf Skolem (2 of 2) (Box 126, Folder 1597)
  - Thoralf Skolem (1 of 2) (Box 126, Folder 1598)
  - Thoralf Skolem (2 of 2) (Box 126, Folder 1599)
  - SL, "Alternative Philosophies as Complementary" (Box 126, Folder 1600)
  - D. Slepian (Box 126, Folder 1601)
  - Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada Grant Application, Imants Barušs (Box 127, Folder 1602)
  - "Solvable Subcases of the Suranyi Reduction Class" by Burton Dreben (Box 127, Folder 1603)
  - "Some Crude Remarks on Contemporary Philosophy" (Box 127, Folder 1604)
  - Some Facts about Kurt Gödel (Box 127, Folder 1605)
  - "Some Half-Baked Remarks on the Mathematical Order", 1965 (Box 127, Folder 1606)
  - "Some Observations about the Relationship between Theory of Relativity and Kantian Philosophy" by Kurt Gödel (Box 127, Folder 1607)
  - "Some Partial Results of the Domino Problem" by Edward F. Moore and Hao Wang (Box 127, Folder 1608)
  - Ernst Specker (1 of 2) (Box 127, Folder 1609)
  - Ernst Specker (2 of 2) (Box 127, Folder 1610)
  - Spoken Compositions (Box 128, Folder 1611)
  - "Strong Partition Properties for Infinite Cardinals" by Eugene M. Kleinberg (Box 128, Folder 1612)
  - "A Substitute of the Method of Truth Tables", Fall, 1946 (Box 128, Folder 1613)
  - "Supplement to 'New Directions'", 1993 (Box 128, Folder 1614)
  - J.W. Swanson (Box 128, Folder 1615)
  - SWF, "The Separation of Wish and Fact" (Box 128, Folder 1616)
  - SWF, "The Separation of Wish and Fact", 1988 (Box 128, Folder 1617)
  - Syntax Paper and Ontological Proof, Gödel-related (Box 128, Folder 1618)
  - "Synthese," Volume 88, Number 2, August 1991 (Box 128, Folder 1619)
  - "Tag Systems and Lag Systems" (Box 128, Folder 1620)
  - "The Taoist Perversion of 20th Century Science" by Michael Billington (Box 129, Folder 1621)
  - "A Tentative Ethical Theory" (Box 129, Folder 1622)
  - "A Tentative Ethical Theory," Term Paper for Philosophy 4a, December 1947 (Box 129, Folder 1623)
  - "Tharp and Conceptual Logic" (Box 129, Folder 1624)
  - "Tharp and Conceptual Logic" (Box 129, Folder 1625)
  - "Tharp and Conceptual Logic" (Box 129, Folder 1626)
  - Tharp Memorial Manuscripts (Box 129, Folder 1627)
  - "Theaters without Actors" (Box 129, Folder 1628)
  - "Theory and Practice in Mathematics," Chapter VII from "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (Box 129, Folder 1629)
  - Thesis, "An Algorithmic Notation for Symbol Manipulation" by Edward Francis Storm, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 1630)
  - Thesis, "A New Decision Procedure in Logic with a Computer Realization" by Joyce Barbara Friedman, 1964 (Box 129, Folder 1631)
  - Thesis, "A New Undecidable Problem with Applications in Logic" by Stål Olav Aanderaa, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 1632)
  - Thesis, "On the Minimum Computation Time of Functions" by Stephen Arthur Cook, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 1633)
  - Thesis, "The Undecidability of the Domino Problem" by Robert Berger, 1964 (Box 130, Folder 1634)
  - Thesis, "The Undecidability of the Turing Machine Immortality Problem" by Philip Kuehne Hooper, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 1635)
  - "They Dreamed of the Genie in the Machine" by Robert L. Schoenfeld (Box 130, Folder 1636)
  - "Thinking about China: Facts and Questions" (Box 130, Folder 1637)
  - Thoughts Related to Husserlian Themes (Box 130, Folder 1638)
  - "Thoughts Related to Husserlian Themes" (Box 130, Folder 1639)
  - "Time", 1993-1994; Includes: “Introductory Note to Gödel’s Papers on Kant and Relativity Theory (for his Collected Works, vol. III” by Howard Stein “Time in Philosophy and in Physics – from Kant and Einstein to Gödel” (Box 130, Folder 1640)
  - "Time in Philosophy and in Physics" (Box 131, Folder 1641)
  - "Time in Philosophy and in Physics", 1993 (Box 131, Folder 1642)
  - "Time in Philosophy and in Physics: From Kant and Einstein to Gödel" (Box 131, Folder 1643)
  - "To and From Philosophy - Discussions with Gödel and Wittgenstein" (Box 131, Folder 1644)
  - "To and From Philosophy (FTP)" (1 of 2) (Box 131, Folder 1645)
  - "To and From Philosophy (FTP)" (2 of 2) (Box 131, Folder 1646)
  - "To Will Businesslike Perspicuity through Logic" (Box 131, Folder 1647)
  - "To Will Businesslike Perspicuity through Logic," "To Will (and Find in Logic) Businesslike Perspicuity" and "To Will Only Perspicuity" (Box 132, Folder 1648)
  - "To Will Only Perspicuity" (Box 132, Folder 1649)
  - "Tolerance and Metalanguages in Carnap's Logic Syntax of Language" by Dave De Vidi and Graham Solomon (Box 132, Folder 1650)
  - TPM, "Two Pillars of Platonism for Mathematics: Varities, Choices, Extensions" (Box 132, Folder 1651)
  - "Turing and the Origins of AI" by Stuart Shanker (Box 132, Folder 1652)
  - "Two Commandments of Analytic Empiricism" (Box 132, Folder 1653)
  - "Two Commandments of Analytic Empiricism," Second Draft (Box 132, Folder 1654)
  - "Two Pillars of Platonism for Mathematics: Varieties, Choices, Extensions" (Box 132, Folder 1655)
  - Typed Notes, Extra Set, 1956-1957 (Box 132, Folder 1656)
  - “Über formal Unentscheidbare säatze der Principia Mathematica und Verwandter Systeme I” by Kurt Gödel (Box 132, Folder 1657)
  - Uhlenbeck Lecture Notes, 1969 (Box 132, Folder 1658)
  - Unfoldered Gödel Manuscript and Notes (Box 132, Folder 1659)
  - Unfoldered Gödel Material (Box 133, Folder 1660)
  - Unfoldered Gödel-related Materials (Box 133, Folder 1661)
  - Unfoldered Manuscript, "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (1 of 2) (Box 133, Folder 1662)
  - Unfoldered Manuscript, "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (2 of 2) (Box 133, Folder 1663)
  - Unfoldered Manuscript, "Mathematical Logic and Philosophy of Mathematics," Chapter 1 from "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (Box 133, Folder 1664)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts (Box 133, Folder 1665)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Tag Systems and Lag Systems” “Mechanical Mathematics and Inferential Analysis” (Box 134, Folder 1666)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “A Survey of Skolem’s Work in Logic” “Russell and Philosophy” “Logic, Computation and Philosophy” “Can Mind do More than Brain?” “Aperiodicity and Constraints” “Term Paper for Philosophy 4a,” 1946 “Toward Mechanical Mathematics” “The Axiomatization of Arithmetic” “On Formalization” “Russell und seine Logik” “Rules and Derived Rules” by Dana Scott “On Engendering an Illusion of Understanding” by Dana Scott “Background to Formalization” by Dana Scott “Locke’s Transcendental Logic: Vignettes of a Reading” by Robert S. Tragesser (Box 134, Folder 1667)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Recursion and Double Recursion” by R.M. Robinson “Recursive Functions” “General Recursive Functions” by Julia Robinson “Entscheidungsproblem und Dominospiele” by H. Hermes (Box 134, Folder 1668)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Who is Responsible for World Philosophy?” by Archie J. Bahm “The Philosophical Background of Magendie’s Physiology” by Owsei Temkin “A Knowledge Representation Based on Belnap’s Four-Valued Logic” by Yuri Kaluzhny and Alexi Yu. Muravitsky (Box 134, Folder 1669)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Philosophy as Gödel Saw It” “Chapter VII: The Liar Belied: Legation in If Logic” “Chapter VIII: Axiomatic Set Theory – Fraenkelstein’s Monster?” “Chapter IX: If Logic as a Framework for Mathematical Theorizing” “Chapter X: Constructivism Reconstructed” “Chapter XI: The Epistemology of Mathematical Objects” (Box 134, Folder 1670)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Fresh Winds in the Philosophy of Mathematics” by Reuben Hersh “Cohen’s Carnap, or Subjectivity is in the Eye of the Beholder” by Burton Dreben “The Continuing Significance of Moore’s Objection to Wittgenstein’s Discussions of Mathematics, 1930-33 and Its Bearing on ‘On Certainty’” by Juliet Floyd “Comments on Koethe’s ‘Objects and Propositions in the Tractatus’” by Juliet Floyd “Chinese Filial Piety and the Oedipus Complex – A Literary and Cultural Comparison” by Youqin Wang (Box 134, Folder 1671)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Reflections on the Concept of A Priori Truth and Its Corruption by Kant” by William W. Tait “Frege versus Cantor and Dedekind: On the Concept of Number” by W.W. Tait “Structuralism and Post-modernism in the Philosophy of Mathematics” by Thomas Tymoczko “Putnam, Quine – and the Facts” by Burton Dreben “Complexity as Thermodynamic Depth” by Seth Lloyd and Heinz Pagels (Box 134, Folder 1672)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “An Approach to Deciding Quickly Boolean Validity” by Bradford Dunham and Hao Wang “Toward Feasible Solutions of the Tautology Problem” by Bradford Dunham and Hao Wang (Box 134, Folder 1673)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Can a Machine Think?” by A.M. Turing “Global Order from Local Sources” by Charles Radin “Aperiodicity and Constraints” by Hao Wang “Truth and Proof: The Platonism of Mathematics” by W.W. Tait “Wittgenstein and the ‘Skeptical Paradoxes’” by W.W. Tait “Plato’s Second Best Method” by W.W. Tait “Some Recent Essays in the History of Philosophy of Mathematics: A Critical Review” by W.W. Tait “Against Intuitionism: Constructive Mathematics is Part of Classical Mathematics” by W.W. Tait (Box 135, Folder 1674)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Some Facts about Kurt Gödel” “Hyperarithmetically Encodable Sets” by Robert M. Solovay “On Ramsay Cardinals” by Bill Mitchell “Large Sets” by Hao Wang “Gödel’s and Some Other Examples of Problem Transmutation” (Box 135, Folder 1675)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Mathematical Games” by Martin Gardner “Undecidable Tiling Problems in the Hyperbolic Plane” by Raphael M. Robinson “Boolean Algebras, Splitting Theorems, and ∆ 0/2 Sets” by Michael D. Morley and Robert I. Soare “A Survey of Skolem’s Work in Logic” “Computability and Tiling Problems” (Box 135, Folder 1676)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “To and From Philosophy – Discussions with Gödel and Wittgenstein” “Frege’s Logicism and the Rigorization of Analysis” by William Demopoulos “Quis Custodiet Ipsos Custodes? Who Watches the Watchers?” by Joshua Lederberg “The Compactness of First-Order Logic: From Gödel to Lindström” by John W. Dawson, Jr. “Fundierung as a Logical Concept” by Gian-Carlo Rota “The Uniqueness of the Natural Numbers” by Charles Parsons (Box 135, Folder 1677)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Über einige Interpretationen von Registermaschinen mit Anwendungen auf Entscheidungsprobleme in der Logik, der Algorithmentheorie und der Theorie formaler Sprachen” by Egon Börger “Recursively Unsolvable Algorithmic Problems and Related Question Reexamined” by E. Börger “Bewisverfahren für den Prädikatenkalkül” by Gerd Veenker (Box 135, Folder 1678)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “The Sellout” by Freeman J. Dyson “Is Physics Legislated by Cosmogony?” by Charles M. Patton and John Archibald Wheeler “On Gentzen’s Proof for the Consistency of Pure Number Theory” by Laszlo Kalmar “The Conceivability of Mechanism” by Norman Malcolm “Statement of Dr. Bruno Bettelheim before the House Special Subcommittee on Education, 1969” “The Unity of Physics” by C.F. von Weizsäcker, translated by Gordon Reece “The Princeton Period” by A. Pais “Über Iterative Algorithmen. I.” by Harald Geppert (Box 135, Folder 1679)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Global Parallel Unification for Question-Answering Systems” by J. Gary Auguston and Jack Minker “The Disjunction Property Implies the Numerical Existence Property” by Harvey Friedman “P-Algebras, An Abstraction from Post Algebras” by George Epstein and Alfred Horn “The Smallest Many-Valued Logic for the Treatment of Complemented and Uncomplemented Error Signals” by Melvin A. Breuer and George Epstein “Multiple-Valued Logic Design and Applications in Binary Computers” by Robert C. Braddock, George Epstein, and Hideki Yamanaka “A Theory of Partial Sets” by Paul C. Gilmore “The Categorization of Tag Systems in Terms of Decidability” “Outline of a Mathematical Theory of Computation” by Dana Scott “A Hilbert-Ackarmann-Herbrand Elimination Method” by John Denton “English as a Formal Language I” by Richard Montague “Some Results on the Length of Proof” by R.J. Parikh (Box 135, Folder 1680)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Includes: “Notes on Wu’s Algorithm for Geometry” “Die Frage der endlich vielen Schritte in der Theorie der Polynomideale” by Grete Hermann (Box 136, Folder 1681)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Corrections, "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (Box 136, Folder 1682)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Correspondence, Includes: “An Outline of Platonist Grammar” by Jerrold L. Katz “Introductory Note to 1947 and 1964” “Interderivability of Seemingly Unrelated Mathematical Statements and the Philosophy of Mathematics” by Guillermo E. Rosado Haddock (Box 136, Folder 1683)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Correspondence, Includes: “An Error in Gödel’s Incompleteness Proofs” by Crispin Hasler (Box 136, Folder 1684)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “An Outline of Platonist Grammar” by Jerrold L. Katz “Introductory Note to 1947 and 1964” “Interderivability of Seemingly Unrelated Mathematical Statements and the Philosophy of Mathematics” by Guillermo E. Rosado Haddock (Box 136, Folder 1685)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes (Box 136, Folder 1686)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “A Supplement to Herbrand” by Burton Dreben “False Lemmas in Herbrand” by Burton Dreben, Peter Andrews, and Stål Aanderaa “A Supplement to Herbrand” by Burton Dreben and John Denton “Axiomatisches Denken” “The Nature of Dialectics” by Hilary Putnam “Explanation and Reference” by Hilary Putnam “Herbrand Analyzing Functions” by Burton Dreben and Stål Aanderaa “Logique Mathématique – Sur la Théorie de la Démonstration, Note on Herbrand, by Hadamard” (Box 136, Folder 1687)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes (Box 136, Folder 1687A)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Images and Models, Similes and Metaphors” by George A. Miller “On the Unreasonable Effectiveness of Mathematics” “Utility Maximization and Melioration: Internalities in Individual Choice” by R.J. Herrnstein, George F. Lowenstein, Drazen Prelec, and William Vaughan, Jr. (Box 137, Folder 1688)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Notes on Forcing” “Some Partial Results on the Domino Problem” by Edward F. Moore and Hao Wang “Non-Recursive Tilings of the Plane I” by William Hanf “Dominoes and the AEA Case of the Decision Problem” (Box 137, Folder 1689)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Wittgenstein on the Trisection of the Angle” by Juliet Floyd “An Error in Gödel” by Crispin Hasler (Box 137, Folder 1690)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Modernization as Perspective” by Jim Peck “Smoking and Society” “Persecution of Smokers” “Refutation Procedures and Search Principles” by Mansfield “CS 2409S (S.A. Cook), Lecture 4,” 1973 “Feasibly Constructive Proofs and the Propositional Calculus” by Stephen A. Cook “Satisfiability is Quasilinear Complete in NQL” by C.P. Schnorr “Axiomatic and Interpretive Semantics for an Algol Fragment” by Stephen A. Cook “Soil Mechanics in Engineering Practice, The Story of a Manuscript 1942-1948” by Ralph B. Peck “A Critical Examination of Dialectics” by Mario Bunge “Diagonal Methods and Strong Cuts in Models of Arithmetic” by Kenneth McAloon (Box 137, Folder 1691)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “An Approach to Quickly Deciding Boolean Validity” “Toward Feasible Solutions of the Tautology Problem” “What is Special about Elementary Logic?” (Box 137, Folder 1692)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Wittgenstein’s Lecture on Ethics” “Truth, Quantification, and Abstract Objects” “A Remark on Modal Logic” (Box 138, Folder 1693)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Mind Brain Machine” “Second Thoughts about Church’s Thesis and Mathematical Proofs” by Elliott Mendelson (Box 138, Folder 1694)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “A Two Level Grammar and Its Parser Generator” by Chih-shung Tang “XYZ: A Family of Hierarchical Languages, Its Design Philosophy” by Chih-sung Tang “A Recursive Theory of Computer Instructions” by Chih-sung Tang “A Reduction Class of Formulas in which All Disjunctions are Binary” by Stål Aanderaa “Freedom and Political Principles” “R.E. Bases by Constructive Arithmetic Relations: Moh Functions and Diophantine Equations” “A Survey of Classes of Primitive Recursive Functions” by S.A. Cook (Box 138, Folder 1695)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “A ‘Natural’ Enumeration of Non-Negative Rational Numbers – An Informal Discussion” “Effective Procedures in Field Theory” by A. Frölich and J.C. Shepherdson “A Problem of Algebraic Manipulation” “Factoring Multivariate Polynomials over Algebraic Number Fields” by Paul S. Wang “On the Decision Problem and the Mechanization of Theorem-Proving in Elementary Geometry” by Wu Wen-tsün (Box 138, Folder 1696)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Can Minds do More than Brains?” “The Rightful Place of Mathematics in Philosophy/To and From Philosophy” “Philosophy and our Real Need” (Box 138, Folder 1697)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Michel Foucault’s History of Culture” by Patricia O’Brien “Thought and Cinema” “Like Writing History with Lightning: Historical Film/Historical Truth” by Robert A. Rosenstone (Box 138, Folder 1698)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Thesis on Kant’s Philosophy and the Establishment of Subjectivity” by Li Zhe-hou, translated by H.C. Pan “Gödel’s and Some Other Examples of Problem Transmutation” “Gödel and Wittgenstein” “Philosophy: Chinese and Western” “Western Philosophy from a Chinese Perspective” (Box 138, Folder 1699)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Necessity, Analyticity, and Apriority” “Knowledge and Logic” (Box 139, Folder 1700)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Notes on Philosophy of Mathematics” “Popular Lectures on Mathematical Logic” “Term Paper for Philosophy 4a” “Formal Logic” “Some Independence Results for Peano Arithmetic” by J.B. Paris “Undecidable Tiling Problems in the Hyperbolic Plane” by Raphael M. Robinson “Initial Segments of Models of Peano’s Axioms” by L.A.S. Kirby and J.B. Paris “Significant Problems with Minimum ‘Raw Material’” “Independence Results for Peano Arithmetic using Inner Models” by J.B. Paris “Initial Segments of Models of Arithmetic” by L.A.S. Kirby “Schwer berechenbare Polynome mit rationale Koeffizientan” by Volker Strassen “Wu’s Algorithm and Feuerbach’s Theorem” “On the Decision Problem and Mechanization of Theorem-Proving in Elementary Geometry” by Wu Wen-tsün “How Many Points on the Line?” (Box 139, Folder 1701)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “New Hopes and Old Fears” by Hao Wang (Box 139, Folder 1702)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, 1960s; Includes: “Logic and Computers” “Logic and Foundations, First Lecture: Mathematics with Minimum ‘Raw Material’” “Logic and Foundations, Second Lecture: Formalization of Mathematical Concepts” (Box 139, Folder 1703)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts and Notes, Gödel-related (Box 139, Folder 1704)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, "From Mathematics to Philosophy" and "Knowledge and Logic" (Box 139, Folder 1705)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, John Rawls (Box 140, Folder 1706)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Revisions to "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (1 of 3) (Box 140, Folder 1707)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Revisions to "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (2 of 3) (Box 140, Folder 1708)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Revisions to "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (3 of 3) (Box 140, Folder 1709)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, "Time in Philosophy and in Physics: From Kant and Einstein to Gödel" and "Imagined Discussions with Gödel and with Wittgenstein" (Box 140, Folder 1710)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Notes, and Correspondence, Includes: “Tautology: How Not to Use a Word” by Burton Dreben and Juliet Floyd “A New Proof of the Gödel Incompleteness Theorem” by George Boolos “Wittgenstein on Mathematics and Following a Rule” “Wittgenstein on 2, 2, 2…: The Opening Remarks on the Foundations of Mathematics” by Juliet Floyd “Wittgenstein versus Turing on the Nature of Church’s Thesis” by S.G. Shanker (Box 141, Folder 1711)
  - Unfoldered Manuscripts, Pages 43-85 and 33-65 (Box 141, Folder 1712)
  - Unfoldered Notebooks, Includes: “The Function of Criticism (T.S. Eliot)” “Paul Bernays” “New Words and Phrases” (Box 141, Folder 1713)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1714)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1715)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1716)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1717)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1718)
  - Unfoldered Notes, Includes: “Toward Feasible Solutions of the Tautology Problem” by Bradford Dunham and Hao Wang (Box 141, Folder 1719)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1720)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 141, Folder 1721)
  - Unfoldered Notes, Includes: “Consistency-Proof for the Generalized Continuum Hypothesis” by Kurt Gödel (Box 141, Folder 1722)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 142, Folder 1723)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 142, Folder 1724)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 142, Folder 1725)
  - Unfoldered Notes (Box 142, Folder 1726)
  - Unfoldered Notes and Manuscripts (Box 142, Folder 1727)
  - Unfoldered Notes and Manuscripts (Box 142, Folder 1728)
  - Unfoldered Notes and Manuscripts, Includes: “A Proof of the Impossibility of Inductive Probability” by Karl Popper and David Miller “Turing’s Philosophy” “Excerpt from a draft of Substitutions, Freebinding, and Freecausation with Perfunctory Recursions and Restatements” by Paul Alan Berent “The Practical Consequences of Metaphysical Beliefs on a Biologist’s Work: An Autobiographical Note” by C.H. Waddington “Subdirectly Irreducible Rings and Arithmetic Local Rings – Some Pathology” by Sin-Min Lee “Anticipation of Universal Instantiation” “Mathematics: Its Trends and Its Tensions” by Mark Kac “Remarks on Present Trends in Mathematical Research” by Lipman Bers “Thoughts on the Roof Article in Mathematics (Encyclopedia Britannica)” by Abraham Robinson “Report on the Mathematical Order” “From China, With Love” by Bill Livant “Bases for Recursively Enumerable Relations” “R.E. Bases by Constructive Arithmetic Relations: Moh Functions and Diophantine Equations” “Unending Chess, Symbolic Dynamics and a Problem in Semigroups” by Marston Morse and Gustav A. Hedlund (Box 142, Folder 1729)